Seydou CISSE

Senior Software Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: cisse.seydou1@yahoo.com Address: Casablanca, Morocco Phone: +212766295337

SUMMARY

With over seven years of rich experience in software development, I have carved out a niche as a seasoned Java developer and evolved into a leadership role as a Lead Developer. My career journey has spanned diverse industries, including finance, retail, energy, and IT, offering me a holistic view of software development across various domains.

EXPERIENCE

Remote

May 2023 - Present

Lead developer

Carrefour Group

- · Lead of a team of 3 developers
- Design of an invoice standardization solution for the Carrefour group
- · Participation in the application architecture of the Carrefour Group's invoice standardization solution
- · Implementation of the standardization application frontend
- · Implementation of a rules engine for invoice validation
- · Management of CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins and Gitlab CI

Casablanca, Morocco

Sep 2021 - May 2023

Software Developer

Attijari IT Africa (Attijariwafa Bank Group)

- Evolutionary and corrective maintenance of a middleware application for scoring credit applications and rating companies
- Design and development of an application for exchanging credit declaration data with Bank Al-Maghrib (Central Bank of Morocco)
- · Design and implementation of a reporting app using Streamserver

Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

Jan 2018 - Aug 2021

Software Developer

Société Nationale de Développement Informatique SNDI

- Design and implementation of the Public Finance Management Information System (SIGFP) of Benin as part of the Economic Management Support Project
- Design and implementation of the Epidemiological Surveillance Information System (SISE) on behalf of the Pasteur Institute CI as part of the fight against COVID-19 in Côte d'Ivoire.
- Implementation of cash statements as part of the Integrated Treasury Management System of the State
 of Côte d'Ivoire

EDUCATION

Tunis, Tunisia

Aug 2016 - Jun 2017

Software Engineer

High School of Communications of Tunis (SUPCOM)

Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

Sep 2015 - Jun 2017

Master in Software Engineering

Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC)

Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

Sep 2012 - Jun 2015

Bachelor in Computer Science

Ecole Supérieure Africaine des TIC (ESATIC)

LANGUAGES

French

Native

English

Intermediate

SKILLS

User-Centric Problem Solving

Project Management

Software architecture

DevOps (Gitlab CI, Kubernetes)

Machine Learning/AI Basics

Collaborative Learner

Agile Methodologies (SCRUM)

Cloud Technologies (AWS, GCP)

DB Management (Postgres, Couchbase)

Version Control (Git, GitHub, GitLab)

Frontend Development (Angular, React)

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

- AZ-900: Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft, 2022
- AWS Cloud Developer, ALX Udacity, 2022

Java Development (Spring, Spring boot)

• SCRUM Foundation Professional Certificate, CERTIPROF, 2022